Guide to the Eyes of Texas television show episodes and summaries collection, 1978-2009 MS 170
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- 1987 episodes, 226846
  - Jan. 24, 1987: Senior Softball League, Houston / John Pouland-Buggy Man, Diboll / 1750 Rancho Dolorus, Webb Co. / Allen House, Belton, 226881 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 333)
  - Jan. 31, 1987: State Gem-Topaz, Mason / Eggleston Log Cabin, Gonzales / Roeder's Bird Food, Bryan / Vanishing River Cruise, Lake Buchanan 10-23-82 / Joyce Renfro-Goard Artist, Zavalla, 226880 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 334)
  - Feb. 7, 1987: Henry Baumgarten, Schulenburg / Martin Steiner-Model RR, Houston / Moody House, Taylor / San Antonio Botanical Garden-Brackenridge Pk, 226879 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 335)
  - Feb. 14, 1987: Forshey Piano Co, Pasadena / Little Red Schoolhouse, Leesville / Martinez Land Grant, Richmond / Hodges Bend, Richmond, 226878 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 336)
  - Feb. 21, 1987: Cannonade Cattle Ranch, Gonzales / Tumbleweed Smith, Big Spring 10-11-80 / Dinosaur Jack Maxwell, Moody / Lillie Machart & TX Oldest Drugstore, Victoria, 226877 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 337)
  - Feb. 28, 1987: Martha Cotera-IT Business, Austin / Virginia Munroe-Baskets, San Antonio / Bob Roberson-Buggy Man, Levelland (1-8-83) / Esther Smith-Piano Lady, Palacios / Keystone Hotel, Lampasas, 226876 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 338)
  - March 7, 1987: Railroad Special. Copper Canyon - Part 1 / Copper Canyon - Part 2 / Tex-Mex Express / Texas State Railroad, 226875 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 339)
  - March 14, 1987: Rice Univ. Info Center, Houston / A.L. Rash-Insulator Collector, Lumberton / Jewel Babb-Healer, Valentine / Dessau Hall, Pflugerville, 226874 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 340)
  - March 21, 1987: Main St. Revitalization, Lufkin / Cauthen House-Shops, Lampasas / Lacy Dogs, Marble Falls 3-6-82 / Museum Natural Science, Houston / Camilla Post Office, San Jacinto Co., 226873 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 341)
  - March 28, 1987: El Paso to Houston at 55mph / Agnese Carter Nelms School, Camden / Hillsboro, Hill County / Governor's Mansion, Austin, 226872 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 342)
  - April 4, 1987: Bernard Sampson-TV Collector, Houston / Sabine Pass Lighthouse / Borglum- Sculptor, San Antonio 2-5-83 / Courtright-Short Gunfight, Fort Worth, 226871 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 343)
  - April 11, 1987: Texas City Disaster Remembered / Darsey General Store, Grapeland / King Vidor-Director, Galveston / Annie Sweat-Doll Collector, Calvert, 226870 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 344)
  - April 18, 1987: Texas Bobsled Team, Austin / Hardin Family, Liberty / Danbury Fish Farm / Brinkmann Bldg Antiques, Comfort, 226869 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 345)
  - April 25, 1987: Killer Bees Approach Texas / Pam Shauck-Dinosaur Artist, Lorena / George Bossley Bait Camp, Sabine Pass / Giddings-Stone Mansion, Brenham, 226868 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 346)
  - May 2, 1987: Dumbeck-Underground House, Elgin / Carrie Rich-Sun Bonnets, Kirbyville / Geo McAdams-Chimney Sweep, Round Rock / Romano Fay's Soda Shoppe, Centerville, 226867 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 347)
  - May 9, 1987: Old Galveston Bridge / Swedes in Texas, Austin / Phil Parr-Country DJ, Lufkin / Jone's Rose Garden, Waco, 226866 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 348)
  - May 16, 1987: Leathers' Playground, Pleasanton / Llano History / Brushy Bill-Billy The Kid?, Hico / Wildflowers, 226865 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 349)
  - May 23, 1987: History of Hacienda Dolores / Floyd Williams-Kiddie Cars, Comfort / Don Hargrove-Glass Artist, Silsbee / Clark Hotel & Museum, Vanhorn / Capitol Replica, West Columbia, 226864 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 350)
  - May 30, 1987: Twitty's Last Restaurant, Hemphill / Harold Coleman-Knife Maker, Bishop / "Super Sweet" Onions, McAllen / TX Parks & Wildlife Mag, Austin 10-31-81 / Peach Tree Gifts & Tea Rm, Fredericksburg, 226863 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 351)
  - June 6, 1987: Largest Sulphur Mine, Pecos / Turnerville UM Church, Round Rock / James Avery-Jeweler, Kerrville / Walburg Mercantile, Walburg, 226862 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 352)
  - Sept. 19, 1987: Bob Roberson-Chuck Wagon, Levelland / 1895 Fort Bend County Jail / General Sidney Sherman / Capt. Vic Delgado-Seaman, Port Isabel / Saving the Town of Chireno, 226861 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 353)
  - Sept. 26, 1987: Senior Center, Dripping Springs / Bill the Shooter, Breckenridge / B-17 WWII Bomber, Houston / Douglas Grocery, Fort Worth / 1894 Opera House, Galveston, 226860 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 354)
  - Oct. 3, 1987: William Huff Diary Studied / James Sylvestor, San Jacinto Hero / Boynton/Ciszek- Artists, Houston / Alligators-Brazos Bend SP, Ft. Bend Co., 226859 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 355)
  - Oct. 10, 1987: Battle of Glorieta Pass, New Mexico / Rotary Boys Club Camp, Willis / Clive Cussler-Author, Galveston / Walter Paye Lane-Mier Expedition Bodies / Dalpaso Hotel, Lamesa, 226858 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 356)
  - Oct. 17, 1987: Reunion-Helicopter Pilots-Korean War / Bill Measures-Oilman, Midland / Sra Francisca Alvarez-Angel of Golied / Humorous Look at Texas Golfers / George Ranch, Richmond, 226857 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 357)
  - Oct. 24, 1987: House Moving by Barge, Beaumont / Buddy Holly-Musician, Lubbock / Vernon Dalhart-Musician, Jefferson / Only Union Monument in Texas / Gene Whitenack-Cowboy, Stieler Monument, Spring, 226856 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 358)
  - Oct. 31, 1987: Matthews - Sauer Beckmann Farm, Stonewall / Louis Kemp, Houston-TX State Cemetery / Lewis - Dos Amigos Honky Tonk, Odessa / "Lady in Gray Taffeta Dress", E. Columbia / Hoover - Edith Moore Nature Sanctuary, Houston, 226855 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 359)
  - Nov. 7, 1987: Dugger-Shrimp Farmer, Port Isabel / J Ventura & J Ford-Collectors, Columbus / Sullivan-Submarine, Galveston / End of 'Ross' Burris Theatre, Sabinal / Indian Emily, Fort Davis, 226854 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 360)
  - Nov. 14, 1987: Christi, Thompson - New Waterfall, Wichita Falls / Paul - Hot Springs of West Texas, Lajitas / Seminole Negro Indian Scouts / Doggett, Henderson - School for Deaf, Houston / Godwin - Deputy Cat-'DC', Kermit, 226853 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 361)
  - Nov. 21, 1987: Billy Sims-Snow Cones, Gainesville / Benficklin-Ghost Town / Carleton Reid-Gemologist, Houston / R.C. Hickman-Photographer, Dallas / Child Photographer / Hazzelbach's Pittsburg Hot Links, 226852 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 362)
  - Nov. 28, 1987: Buffalo Bayou Paddleboats, Houston / Wildlife Management, Carta Valley / Walter Williams-Last Confed Soldier / Gage Bike Shop, Buda / Frontier Village, Denison, 226851 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 363)
  - Dec. 05, 1987: Frederickson, Ochs - TX Conservation Center, Canyon / Robert Howard-Conan, Cross Plains / Buchannan Dam / The Heights, Early Houston Suburb, 226850 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 364)
  - Dec. 12, 1987: Whooping Cranes, Aransas Wildlife Refuge / Bird Caretaker, Midland / Albert Martin - Little Known Hero / Old Socorro, 226849 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 365)
  - Dec. 12, 1987 (Christmas Special): Tree Lighting, Downtown Houston / Sam Houston Park / Ornament Lady / San Antonio Christmas / Cowboy Christmas Baseball / Jefferson/Marshall, 226848 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 366)
  - Jan. 2, 1987: A walking Tour of Columbus / Alfred Hayne, Fort Worth / Musical trip from El Pasto to El Capitan / Mildred Dupuis - One of the First Female Pharmicists in the state, The Heights / Woodcarver Gene Zesch and the James River, Hill Country, 226847 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 367)
- 1988 episodes, 226815
  - KPRC's summary of 1988 episodes, 226845 (Folder 11)
  - Jan. 9, 1988: Dutch Belted Cattle, Brenham / Whirter - Sancties Movement / A Reunion in the Heights / M&M Candy / Aritst in the Oil Patch, West Texas / Cleaning up Cemetaries, Gonzales County, 226844 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 368)
  - Jan. 16, 1988: Bell, Dearing, Fabian - Windy Knoll Farm, Magnolia / Fletcher Stockdale-TX Governor, 30 Days / A&M Sea Camp-Gulf, Galveston / Historic Oak Island Church, San Antonio / Joe Peacock-Sandcarver, Jacksonville, 226843 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 369)
  - Jan. 23, 1988: JL Nixon-Mystery Students, Humble / B Hollinsworth-Cuckoo Clocks, Ft. Worth / Kellys'-Cedar Posts, Gatesville / Henry Ralph Wolley-Gov Willie, Kilgore / O''Tyson-Ginocchio Hotel, Marshall, 226842 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 370)
  - Jan. 30, 1988: Dr. Geo Woolfolk-Prarie View A&M / David Mitschke-Character, Loebau / Henry Flipper-Engineer, El Paso / Washington, Judge Roy Bean - Beanville, San Antonio / Helena Texas, 226841 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 371)
  - Feb. 06, 1988: Stevenson, Beauchamp - Taylor-Stevenson Ranch, Houston / Babe Aycock-Mayor, Mart / George Childress-Texas Constitution / Jim Jeffries-Rocking Horses, Crockett / San Fernando Cathedral, San Antonio, 226840 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 372)
  - Feb. 13, 1988: Smith, Towery - A.G.E. Center, Austin / Ollie Matson-Football, Trinity / Wall, Broocks, Parker, Malone - Wall-Brooks-Border Fued, San Augustine / Hoffarts Store, Dobbins, 226839 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 373)
  - Feb. 20, 1988: Kooch, Woerner - Burlap Wool Sacks, Fredericksburg / Elmer Kleb-Hermit, Cypress / Reagan Wiseman-Clocks, La Vernia / Bean's-Dinosaur Gardens, Moscow, 226838 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 374)
  - Feb. 27, 1988: Goard Farmer, Zavalla / Hilary Page, Houston / Washington Cemetary / Robot Dinosaurs, Dallas and Houston, 226837 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 375)
  - March 5, 1988: Bottle Collector, Austin / George Washington Glasscock / Lytton Springs / Mama Sugar, Arcola / Dean Boswell Mansion, Lamesa, 226836 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 376)
  - March 12, 1988: LBJ Library, Austin / Borski's Nightclub, Willis / Black Beauty Ranch, Brownsboro / 7-A Ranch Resort, Wimberley, 226835 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 377)
  - March 19, 1988: New York Cheesecake, Made in TX / Mario Sanchez, Houston / Dizzy Dean, Baseball Great / Mail Order Bears, Fredericksburg / The Killing of a Sheriff, Fort Stockton, 226834 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 378)
  - March 26, 1988: Cushman Motor Scooter Collector, Rosenberg / Couple living in old Dr. Pepper Bottling Plant, Greenville / Phrenologist, Houston / Texas Forest Festival, Lufkin, 226833 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 379)
  - April 2, 1988: Jollyville, TX / Wool Spinner, Greenville / Oveta Culp Hobby, Killeen and Houston / Toy Show, Victoria, 226832 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 380)
  - April 09, 1988: Levi Deike-Postmaster, Hye / Sullivan Ross, College Station / Vietnamese Immigrants, Port Arthur / Billy Bull-Welder/Artist, Port Lavaca / Beautiful Lake Buchanan, 226831 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 381)
  - April 16, 1988: Ed Sims, Spur Company, Uvalde / Albert Sidney Johnson-Confederate Hero / Miss Hattie-'Bawdy House' San Angelo / Larry Ludtke-Sculptor, Houston / Piper - Driftwood Country Store, 226830 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 382)
  - April 23, 1988: Saving Heritage Village, Woodville / Peniel (Now Greenville) Tx / Fort Phantom, Abilene / Pierce - Blessing & The Blessing Hotel, 226829 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 383)
  - April 30, 1988: Hadj-Casablanca Restaurant, Houston / Van Cliburn, Kilgore / Williamson-Country Store, Cushing / Frank O'Pry-Ford Mustangs, Beaumont / Schakelford Co. Courthouse, 226828 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 384)
  - May 07, 1988: Bill Finck-Cigar Co., San Antonio / Francisco Madero-TX Independence / Wm Martin-Pin Oak Horseman / Reese - Red Eagle-Medicine Man, Nacogdoches / Rocky Rest/Airy Mount-Homes, Burnet, 226827 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 385)
  - May 14, 1988: Friends of Willis Library / John Grivich-Bluebird Man, Huntsville / Settlement of Hutto, Williamson Co. / Shake Russell-Musician, Houston, 226826 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 386)
  - May 21, 1988: Ed Bourdon, Old Timey Photographer / Senior Pickers / Artisan Field, Houston / Bird Sound Library, Huntsville / Gillard Duncan House, Liberty, 226825 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 387)
  - May 28, 1988 (Music Show): Barker Texas History Center, Austin / Duke Peacock, 226824 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 388)
  - Sep. 3, 1988: Cannon - Exekiel Airship, Pittsburg / Oatmeal, Burnet County / The Battle of Mansfield / Hughes - Annual Texas Archaeoligical Society Field School, Perryton / Hale - Corpus Christi Bay, 226823 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 389)
  - Sep 10, 1988: Shows - Cemetary Cleaning, Terryville / Turk - Pegasus, the Flying Red Horse, Dallas / Martin Ruter profile, Rutersville / The Jimmie Rodgers Jubilee, Kerrville / Fort leaton, Presidio / Ben Leaton - A Scalphunter, 226822 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 390)
  - Oct. 15, 1988:Texas-Mexico Park, Big Bend / Robinson's-Big Band Buffs, Lovelady / William Brann, Waco / 'Hobo Haven', Fate / Windsurfing, Corpus Christi, 226821 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 392)
  - Oct. 22, 1988: Fincastle Farms, Larue / Homer Rainey, UT President, Austin / 'Adopt a Building', Corpus Christi / Honey Creek Nature Preserve, Boerne / Old City Park, Dallas, 226820 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 393)
  - Oct. 29, 1988: Governor Price Daniel / Bremond Block, Austin / Yacht Club Hotel, Port Isabel / McDonald Observatory, Ft. Davis, 226819 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 394)
  - Dec. 17, 1988: Artifacts of Underground Houston / Amateur Ice Skaters, Dallas / Johnson - Raleigh House, Ingram / Ivey - Perry Mansion, Terlingua, 226818 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 401)
  - Dec. 24, 1988: TX Loner RV Club, Corsicana / Church Steeple Co., Henderson / Bonarrigo - Messina Hof Vineyards, Bryan / Doris Jackson-Santa Dolls, Lake Jackson / Felix Harris-Voodoo Art, Beaumont, 226817 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 402)
  - Dec. 31, 1988: Hotter-N-Hell 100 Bike Race, Wichita Falls / Greenhaw Family, Mesquite / Cowboy Breakfast, Palo Duro Canyon / Tonkawa Cave, Clifton, 226816 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 403)
- 1989 episodes, 226785
  - KPRC's summary of 1989 episodes, 226814 (Folder 12)
  - Feb. 18, 1989: Half Moon Saloon, Shiner / TX Governor- S.W.T. Latham / Depot Special Learning Center, Henderson / Judy Roberts, Jerry Booher -Wood Artist, Lufkin / Fort Lancanster, Ozona, 226813 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 410)
  - Feb. 25, 1989: Locket, Flaherty, Marks - Early Salt Grass Trail to Houston / Seige of the Alamo / C. Pickering-Coca Cola Buff, Orange / Ward - BMW Farms-Learning Center, Brookshire, 226812 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 411)
  - March 04, 1989: Dallas Market Center / John Moore House, Seguin / Tule Canyon, Panhandle / Texas Craze in London / Beyond big Bend - Candelaria, 226811 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 412)
  - March 11, 1989: Tragedy of LaBahia, Goliad / B. Ledbetter-Pet Caskets, Brenham / Lowell Fulsom-Blues Singer, Dallas / XIT Empire, Dalhart/Panhandle, 226810 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 413)
  - March 18, 1989: Ray Bailey-Architect, Houston / Old Jail House, Benjamin / Burning of Paris, Texas / Jesse Jones Park-Nature Center, Humble / View of Davis Mountain Range, 226809 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 414)
  - March 25, 1989: J. Henthorn-Knife Maker, Tulia / J. Thomas Wildflowers, Eagle Lake / Vincent Hechler-Windmills, Danbury / Two Miller Houses, Old City Park-Dallas, 226808 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 415)
  - April 01, 1989:Tom Proudfoot-TM, Navasota / J.P. Harry Lesser, Chappell Hill / Quannah Parker-Indian Warrior / Cook, Sheuer, Starrs - WPA Texas Post Office Art / Paul Walker, Lee Phipps - Dinner Bells, Woodville, 226807 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 416)
  - April 08, 1989: Ron Wade-G.H. bush Collection, Longview / Henry Wolff-Columnist, Victoria Advocate / Temple &Louie Abernathy / Sue Bracken-Flower Ladies, Woodville / McFaddin-Ward Home, Beaumont, 226806 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 417)
  - April 15, 1989: Trail of Sam Houston-Show #307 / Huey P. Meaux-Music Producer, Winnie / Eastland, Moseby, Waterson - Eastland Cemetery Cleanup / Salado College, Salado, 226805 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 418)
  - April 22, 1989: Russ Butler-Brick Factory, Elgin / Thomas Rusk - Texas Leader / C.W. Post-The Man &The Town / Austin "Cowboy" Doolittle, Sealy / National Wildflower Research Center, Austin, 226804 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 419)
  - April 29, 1989: Frazier Concrete Works, Hempstead / "Dogs at the Alamo" - Matthews, Hurlburt, Boyce / "King Cotton" / Arthur B. Rogers - Spring Lake Park Hotel, San Marcos / Sculpture Park, Liberty Hall, 226803 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 420)
  - May 06, 1989: Prairie Schooner Hotel - Worlds Smallest Hotel, Bandera /Bungy Grant, Promoter - Flower Gardens Reef, Gulf of Mexico / Henry Rosenburg, Galveston / Air Conditioning The Alamo / Long Cabin Village, Fort Worth, 226802 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 421)
  - May 13, 1989: 1855 La Reunion-French Settlement / American Bald Eagle-Lake Buchanan / Parham Antique Lights, Bastrop / Walking Tour of Columbus, 226801 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 422)
  - May 20, 1989: Yvonne Streit-Brookwood, Brookshire / Jim West Mansion, Clear Lake / Bobby Layne-Football Great, Dallas / Sheep Shearing Contest, San Angelo / Painted Churches Tour, Schulenburg, 226800 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 423)
  - May 27, 1989: Mark Dandre-Farrier, Bayside / Camp Ben McCulloch, Driftwood / John Gates-Barbed Wire / Aref Droupy-Alcalde Hote, Gonzales / San Jacinto Monument construction, 226799 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 424)
  - Sept. 16, 1989: Pinky Brown-Cattle Auctions, Luling / Lorenzo De Zavala / Fiddler's Contest 1969, Crockett / Spindletop, Gladys City, 226798 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 425)
  - Sept. 23, 1989: Saving Oaks- Texas A&M, College Station / Tee Pee Motel, Wharton / Model A Club 1969, Houston / Scented Chip Factory, San Antonio / Nimitz Center, Fredericksburg, 226797 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 426)
  - Sept. 30, 1989: Firefighting School, College Station / Bicycle Shop, San Antonio / Albert Clinton Horton / William B Travis &James B Bonham, 226796 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 427)
  - Oct. 28, 1989: Casserole Business, Brenham / Ships in Lightbulbs, Texas City / "Texas Lillie" / Gay Harris-Rock Fence Builder, Wimberley / Fort Brown, Brownsville, 226795 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 431)
  - Nov. 04, 1989: Bess Williams-Blind Shell Collector, Surfside / Wurstfest 1969, New Braunfels / Alaska Annexation-Size of Texas / Harrisburg History / Caddo &LBJ Grasslands, Bonham, 226794 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 432)
  - Nov. 11, 1989: Dena's Diner, Alice / Woody Woodrome-Singing School, Woodville / Sabine Pass / Gaston-Singing Dobermans 1972, Goodrich / Hotel Turkey, Turkey, 226793 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 433)
  - Nov 18, 1989: Bird Rescue, Harlingen / Doan's Crossing, Vernon / Fidel Castro-Visit to Texas / Charlie the Buzzard, Flatonia / Gatesville Jail, 226792 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 434)
  - Nov. 25, 1989: Los Ebanos Ferry-Hand Drawn / Huebner Cattle Drive-Bay City to Matagorda / Clarksville Pottery, Austin / All Girl Rodeo, Hereford, 226791 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 435)
  - Dec. 02, 1989: Apple Industry, Medina / Connie Hager-Bird Lady, Rockport 1972 / Jewelry for dogs, Houston / Texas Prison Museum, Huntsville, 226790 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 436)
  - Dec. 09, 1989: Novel Toys, Canton / Bea's Steakhouse-Doors Open, Anson / Lake Livingston, Onalaska / Football Fever, Iowa Park / Dulcimer Factory, Fredericksburg, 226789 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 437)
  - Nov. 23, 1989: 2nd Monday Trade Days, Bowie / Rose Growing Competition, Blue Lake / Texas Bob Reinhardt, Fort Davis / Old Glory, Texas / Fall Leaves-Lost Maples Park, 226788 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 438)
  - Dec. 16, 1989: Poinsettia Factory, Brenham / Milt Larkin-Jazz Great, Houston / Gordon Scoot-Oriental Rug Maker, Tulia / Marbridge Ranch, Austin / Moon Players - White Rock, Dallas, 226787 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 439)
  - Dec. 25, 1989: Davis Ceramic Christmas Village, Bracketville / Barton - Community's "Helping Hand", West / Rattlesnake Bomber Base, Pyote / Kristkindl Celebration, Fredericksburg / Christmas Tree Forest, Yoakum, 226786 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 440)
- 1990 episodes, 226747
  - KPRC's summary of 1990 episodes, 226784 (Folder 13)
  - Jan. 06, 1990: Gary Willeford-Pigeon Breeder, Hughes Springs / James Lee Baltimore-1983 @ 108, Kirbyville / C.M. Rogers-TX Boast Cards, Austin / Red Cockaded Woodpecker, Sam Houston Forest, 226783 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 441)
  - Jan. 13, 1990: Lifetime Learning Center, Austin / Louisiana Gov. Earl Long-Galveston Hospital / Elizabeth and Clarence Bradley - Truck Driving Team / Sam Malone-Cable TV Host, San Augustine / Red River Valley Museum, Vernon, 226782 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 442)
  - Jan. 20, 1990: Archer City Homecoming/Texasville / Texas Forestry Museum, Lufkin / John Henry Faulk (reporting), Gary James(interviewing) - James Avery Lomax, TX Folk Music / Gladys Porter Zoo, Brownsville, 226781 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 443)
  - Jan. 27, 1990: History of Turpentine, Spurger / Fred Lowery-Whistler, Jacksonville / U.S. / Mexican War - TX to Union / James Surls-Tree Artist, Splendora / Hidalgo Co. Museum, Edinburg, 226780 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 444)
  - Feb. 3, 1990: Kohl - Travelers Hotel, Denison / Salar - Wood Carver, Cypress / Remembering Jim Blakely of Freer / Gray - Circus Man, Jefferson, 226779 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 445)
  - Feb. 10, 1990: Riehle - Champion Paper Company, Lufkin / Cliett - Republic of Eneri / Angle - Snow Cone Empire, Knox City / Stubbs - Life and times of shootist Clay Allison, Pecos, 226778 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 446)
  - Feb. 17, 1990: Woolridge - Digging Back into the Ice Age, Kingsland / Cohen - Dog House Builder, Fresno / Governor Pendleton Murrah, profile / Knippa - One of the Last "Mom & Pop" Telephone Companies in the State / Clark - Artists, Jefferson, 226777 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 447)
  - Feb. 24, 1990: Tuttle - Bat Roosts in Texas / Sellers - Woodcrafter, Kerrville / Jerome Nowotny - Beer Bottle Collector, New Braunfels / Colonel E.M. House, profile / Moore, Dobbs, Patterson - Wiley Hotel, Garrison, 226776 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 448)
  - March 3, 1990 (20th Aniversary Show), Big Bend: Carter - Big Bend Stables / Latimer, Wellman, Maxwell, Barker, Goldman, Newsome - Big Bend Trail Ride, Day 1 / Potter - Big Bend Trail Ride, Day 2, 226775 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 449)
  - March 10, 1990: Uriegas - Racehorse Training Lady, Brady / NASA, Clear Lake / Brumder - Blacksmith, Georgetown / Conkin, McMullen - Blue Lagoon, Huntsville, 226774 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 450)
  - March 17, 1990: Bentsen White Rhino Ranch, Hidalgo / Jordan, Vance, Finnigan, Polk, Mendoza - Women in Texas History / Fracsand Business, Voca / Brunner, McKinney - Telephone Museum, Corpus Christi, 226773 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 451)
  - March 24, 1990: Ada Davis-Pig Trainer, San Marcos / Casa De Palmas Hotel, McAllen / Joe Burch-Corvair Cars, Dallas-1979 / History of Bagdad, Texas / Art of American West, Houston, 226772 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 452)
  - March 31, 1990: New Post Office, Jonesville / Bea Svamera's TX History Class / Kemple, Hammer, Weishoff, Corey - Rodeo Cowboys / Dwight Eisenhower Birthplace-Denison, 226771 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 453)
  - April 07, 1990: Fort Worth Nature Center / Circus Town, Gainsville / Boyd Family Reunion, Callihan Co. / Alfred Muller-Architect, Galveston, 226770 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 454)
  - April 14, 1990: H.L. Scott-Furniture Restorer, Houston / Cuban Missle Crisis / Harris' Porcelain Art, Liberty / Samuell Educational Farm, Mesquite, 226769 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 455)